Talk on Evening Program before Sahasrara Puja, Cabella Ligure, May 3rd, 1996
Program Wieczorny przed Pudźą Sahasrara 3 maja 1996 Kampus, Cabella Ligure, Włochy
It has been such a great pleasure
To była tak wielka przyjemność
and glorification of Sahaja Yoga today,
i wychwalanie Sahadźa Jogi dzisiaj.
I remember the day when it started,
Pamiętam dzień jej rozpoczęcia,
on the 5th May 1970.
5 maja 1970 roku.
And today I see all of you so much
A dzisiaj widzę was wszystkich tak bardzo
engulfed in the Divine love and Divine power.
ogarniętych Boską miłością i Boską mocą.
The whole thing shows one very great,
Całe to wydarzenie ukazuje jedną bardzo wielką,
fundamental thing, of Sahasrara:
fundamentalną rzecz dotyczącą Sahasrary:
that people from so many countries integrated together. Integrated.
to, że ludzie z tak wielu krajów zintegrowali się ze sobą. Zintegrowali.
It was Sahaj, spontaneous, but every way
To było „Sahadźa” – spontaniczne, pod każdym względem;
and there was no confusion, there’s no quarrelling, no fighting, nothing.
nie było zamieszania, kłótni, walki, niczego.
Such an integration, spontaneous,
Taka integracja, spontaniczna,
whether it is on the stage or stage of life.
czy to na scenie, czy na scenie życia.
Now, as we are all global personalities,
Teraz, skoro wszyscy jesteśmy osobowościami globalnymi,
we are all integrated and those who were acting
jesteśmy zintegrowani, a ci, którzy występowali,
were enjoying as well as the ones who were looking at them were also enjoying in the same manner.
czerpali z tego radość, podobnie jak ci, którzy ich oglądali.
It was such a good also integration between the one who was acting,
To była także wspaniała integracja między występującymi,
or the all those who were there, and all those who were watching –
a wszystkimi tymi, którzy ich oglądali –
I couldn’t understand whether the people who are seeing them are also acting,
nie potrafiłam odróżnić, czy ludzie patrzący również występują,
or also those who are acting are also seeing.
czy też ci występujący również patrzą.
It was a beautiful blending I must say,
Muszę rzec, że było to piękne połączenie
and I congratulate all the leaders of all these five countries,
i gratuluję liderom wszystkich tych pięciu krajów,
who have contributed so well to this deep sense of integration.
którzy tak bardzo przyczynili się do tego głębokiego poczucia jedności.
Not that is the integration within that is important
Nie tylko integracja wewnętrzna jest ważna
– of course that’s very important for a personality, but for our work,
– oczywiście jest ona kluczowa dla osobowości – ale dla naszej pracy,
for our global emancipation we need integration of all the nations,
dla naszego globalnego wyzwolenia, potrzebujemy integracji wszystkich narodów
and understanding of all the nations,
i zrozumienia wszystkich narodów,
because these barriers are created by human beings, not by God Almighty.
bo te bariery zostały stworzone przez ludzi, a nie przez Boga Wszechmogącego.
So we have transcended those barriers,
Przekroczyliśmy więc te bariery,
and the way we are all sitting together in a complete integrated mood is –
a sposób, w jaki wszyscy siedzimy razem w nastroju pełnej integracji, jest...
you don’t know what your Mother feels, I, I just can’t believe
nie wiecie, co czuje wasza Matka. Po prostu nie mogę uwierzyć,
that in such a short time this we have achieved,
że w tak krótkim czasie to osiągnęliśmy;
in My lifetime I can see all these things happening.
że za Mojego życia mogę widzieć, jak to wszystko się dzieje.
So it was such a beautiful
To była więc taka piękna,
Sahaja, spontaneous, creation of the Spirit of this integration,
Sahadźa, spontaniczna kreacja Ducha tej integracji.
and I congratulate all the leaders for this,
Gratuluję tego wszystkim liderom
and we all should thank them, for giving us this beautiful
i wszyscy powinniśmy im podziękować za podarowanie nam tej pięknej,
integrated, Sahaj-spontaneous
zintegrowanej, Sahadźa – spontanicznej,
illustration of Sahaj character.
ilustracji charakteru Sahadźa.
Thank you very much. May God bless you all.
Dziękuję bardzo. Niech Bóg błogosławi was wszystkich.